主演：柯克・道格拉斯
光 荣 之 路
导演：斯坦利・库布里克
“法国 1916年”
德国和法国之间的战争
War began between Germany and France
开始于1914年8月3日
on August 3, 1914.
5周后 德国军队已经突破到
Five weeks later, the German army had smashed its way...
离巴黎不到18英里的地方
to within 18 miles of Paris.
被打得灰头土脸的法军 却奇迹般地在马恩河集结
There, the battered French miraculously rallied their forces at the Marne River...
经过一系列出奇制胜的反击 把德国人赶了回去
and in a series of unexpected counterattacks ...  Detail, halt! Drove the Germans back.
前线稳固了
The front was stabilized...
不久后形成了一条高度设防、没有缝隙的战壕
then shortly afterwards developed into a continuous line... of heavily fortified trenches...
曲曲折折绵延500英里
zigzagging their way 500 miles...
从英吉利海峡一直到瑞士边境
from the English Channel to the Swiss frontier.
到了1916年 经过两年惨烈的的堑壕战
By 1916, after two grisly years of trench warfare...
战线几乎没有改变
the battle lines had changed very little.
有效的攻击都是数百码外的
Successful attacks were measured in hundreds of yards...
数十万士兵因此丧生
and paid for in lives by hundreds of thousands.
Broulard将军到了 长官
General Broulard, sir.
你好啊 George
Hello, George. How are you?
Paul 再次见到你太好了 真是太好了
Paul, wonderful seeing you again. Really wonderful.
你这真是金碧辉煌啊 是第一流的
Well, this is splendid. It's superb.
气派 非常气派
It's grand, very grand.
我是试着让工作环境舒服点
Well, I've tried to create a pleasant atmosphere in which to work.
那你干的不错啊 看看这些地毯和绘画 我希望能有你这样好的品味
Well, you've succeeded marvelously. I wish I had your taste in carpets. - Oh! - And pictures.
你过奖了 George 过奖了 坐吧
You're much too kind, George. Much too kind.Sit down, George.
- 谢谢  - 其实我没有改动多少
- Thankyou.I really haven't done very much.
我刚搬来的时候差不多就是这样
The place is much the same as it was when I moved in.
Paul 我这次来是关于一件大事的
Paul, I've come to see you about something big.
这是最高机密 不能轻易告诉下属
It's top secret and must go no further than your chief of staff...
除非他的谨慎值得你信任
and not to him unless you can trust his discretion.
当然
Of course.
为了即将展开的进攻 这条战线上正在集结一批部队
A group of armies is forming on this front for an offensive very soon.
总部决心来一个彻底的突破
Headquarters is determined to make a complete breakthrough.
- 你笑什么？ - 很抱歉
- Why are you smiling? - I'm really sorry.
刚刚有一瞬间 我想我知道你要说什么 请继续说吧
I thought for just a moment I knew what you were going to say. Please go on.
我从不知道你会读心术 你认为我要说什么？
I never knew you were a mind reader. What did you think I was about to say?
- 跟Ant Hill有关  - 你确实会读心术
- Something about the "Anthill  - You are a mind reader.
好吧 这是一处要塞 又在我的防区内
Well, it is a key position. It's in my sector.
完全坦白地讲 我听到了一些传言
To be perfectly honest, I've heard some talk.
- 你知道 总部没有真正的秘密的  - 你怎么看？
You know, there's nothing really secret around headquarters.- Well, what do you think?
就整个德军在本防区的布防来看 这处要塞是关键
It's the key to the whole German position in this sector.
他们已经守了一年了
They've held on to it for a year now...
看起来 只要他们愿意 再守一年也没问题
and it looks as though they'll hold on to it for another year if they want to.
Paul 我接到正式命令 最晚在10号 必须拿下Ant Hill
Paul, I have formal orders to take the Ant hill no later than the 10th.
就是后天  - 这几乎称得上可笑 你不觉得吗？
That's the day after tomorrow. - That comes pretty close to being ridiculous, don't you think?
如果我真这样想的话 我就不会来这了
I don't imagine I'd be here if I really thought that.
Paul 如果在军中有人能为我做这件事 那这个人就是你
Paul, if there's one man in this army who can do this for me, it's you.
不可能 绝对不可能
It's out of the question, George. Absolutely out of the question.
我的师被打得七零八落
My division was cut to pieces.
剩下的部队处于不利形势 想守住防线都有困难 更不可能攻下Ant Hill
What's left of it is in no position to even hold the Ant hill, let alone take it.
很抱歉 但这是事实
I'm sorry, but that's the truth.
好吧 我还要告诉你一些别的事情
Well, Paul, there was something else I wanted to tell you.
但是我敢肯定你会误解我的动机
However, I'm sure that you'll misunderstand my motives in mentioning it.
- 是什么事？ - 噢 你一定会误解的
- What was it? - Oh. You'd be bound to misunderstand.
但是 作为朋友 也许我应该告诉你
However, as your friend, maybe I should tell you.
你想说什么？
What are you trying to say, George?
Paul 总部传出流言 正在考虑让你统领第12军
Paul, talk around headquarters is that you are being considered for the 12th Corps.
- 第12军？ - 是的 再加一颗星（代表职衔的星章）
- The 12th Corps? - Yes, and with that, another star.
我已尽我所能 推动此事
Now, I've pushed it all I can.
第12军需要一位能打仗的将军 你早就该得到这颗星了
The 12th Corps needs a fighting general, and you're overdue on that star.
咱俩都明白 你的履历足够优秀
Now, we both know that your record is good enough...
以至于你可以根据刚才所说的理由 拒绝这项任务
for you to refuse this assignment on the grounds you've stated.
没有人会质疑你的观点 他们只会去另找他人执行这个任务
No one would question your opinion. They'd simply get someone else to do the job.
所以 你不应该让这些影响你的观点 Paul
So you shouldn't let this influence your opinion, Paul.
噢 抱歉 来杯科尼亚克白兰地? - 不 谢谢 Paul 晚饭前我不喝
Oh, I'm sorry. Have a cognac? - No, thanks, Paul, not before dinner.
George 我要为8千名士兵的生命负责
George, I'm responsible for the lives of 8,000 men.
与之相比 我的抱负算什么？
What is my ambition against that?
与之相比 我的名誉算什么？
What is my reputation in comparison to that?
我的士兵是第一位的 George
My men come first of all, George,
他们也清楚这一点 - 我知道
...and those men know it too  - I know that they do.
你看 George 他们知道我绝不会让他们失望的
You see, George, those men know that I would never let them down.
这是不言而喻的
That goes without saying.
对我而言 一名士兵的生命 比法国所有职衔、奖章和荣誉更有意义
The life of one of those soldiers means more to me...
than all the stars and decorations and honors in France.
所以 你觉得
So...you think
你的军队目前的战斗力 不足以发起这次进攻？
this attack is absolutely beyond the ability of your men at this time?
我没这么说 George
I didn't say that, George.
一旦这些士兵的战斗欲望被燃起 没有什么做不到的
Nothing is beyond those men, once their fighting spirit is aroused.
Paul 如果你觉得这次进攻计划不明智 我不想强迫你
Paul, I don't want to push you into it if you think it's ill-advised.
别担心 George 你试试就知道 你不可能强迫我
Don't worry, George. You couldn't do that ifyou tried.
当然 如果有炮火支援将会完全不一样
Of course, artillery would make an enormous difference.
你能给我提供什么样的炮火支援？ - 唔 我会去弄清楚的
What artillery support can you give me? - Well, I'll see.
增援呢？ - 我们会尽力
What about replacements? - We'll see what we can do
但是我确信 你能用你手头的部队完成任务
but I feel sure that you can get along with what you have.
也许刚刚好能完成 噢 Paul
- Might just do it. -Oh, Paul.
我就知道来找你是对的 你就是拿下Ant Hill的人
I knew that I was right to come to you. You are the man to take the Ant hill.
至于那颗星……- 那与我的决定无关！
Now, as far as that star is concerned ... - That had nothing to do with my decision.
如果有关 它会使我做出相反的决定
If anything, it would sway me the other way.
我完全明白 Paul
I realize that perfectly, Paul.
对了 你说要什么时候攻下它？
Now, when do you say you see this coming off?
不迟于后天 - 我们或许能做到！
No later than the day after tomorrow. We just might do it.
你好 士兵 准备好多杀些德国人了吗？
Hello there, soldier. Ready to kill more Germans?
是的 长官  - 你叫什么名字 士兵？
Yes, sir. - What's your name, soldier?
长官 二等兵Ferol A连的  - 啊哈 你结婚了吗 士兵？
Sir, Private Ferol, Company "A." - Uh-huh. Are you married, Private?
没有 长官 - 那么 你母亲一定为你感到骄傲
No, sir.Well, I'll bet your mother's proud of you.
是的 长官- 好的 继续努力 士兵 祝你好运
Yes, sir - Well, carry on, Private, and good luck to you
是的 长官！谢谢 长官！
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
早上好 将军 - 早上好
Good morning, General  - Good morning.
你好 士兵 - 长官
Hello there, soldier.
准备好多杀些德国人了吗？ - 是的 长官
Ready to kill more Germans? - Yes, sir.
啊哈 我看见你在擦拭你的步枪
Aha! Working over your rifle, I see.
好 就该这样做 步枪是士兵最好的朋友
Well, that's the way. It's a soldier's best friend.
你对它好 它会永远对你好
You be good to it, and it'll always be good to you.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
好吧 祝你好运 士兵
Well, uh, good luck to you, soldier.
继续努力吧 - 谢谢 长官
Carry on  - Thankyou, sir.
你好 士兵
Hello there, soldier.
准备好多杀些德国人了吗？
Ready to kill more Germans?
一切都好吗 士兵？
Well, is everything all right, soldier?
一切都好 是的 长官 我很好
All right? Yes, sir, I'm all right.
啊哈 好样的
Aha. Good fellow.
你结婚了吗 士兵？ - 结婚？我 结婚了吗？
Are you married, soldier? - Married? Me, married?
是的 你有妻子吗？ - 妻子？我有妻子吗？
Yes. Have you got a wife? - A wife? Have I got a wife?
长官 他有点炮弹休克症
Sir, he's a bit shell-shocked.
你说什么 中士 世上就不存在炮弹休克症
I beg your pardon, Sergeant. There is no such thing as shell shock.
你有妻子吗 士兵？ 我的妻子？
Have you got a wife, soldier? - My wife?
我的妻子 是的 我有妻子
My wife. Yes, I have a wife.
我再也见不到她了 我会死在战场上
I'm never gonna see her again. I'm gonna be killed.
振作点！你就像一个胆小鬼！
Get a grip on yourself! You're acting like a coward!
我是个胆小鬼 长官 - 振作起来 士兵！
I am a coward, sir. - Snap out of it, soldier!
中士 我要你立即把这小婴儿调离我的团！
Sergeant, I want you to arrange for the immediate transfer of this baby out of my regiment!
我不希望其他的勇士被他感染
I won't have other brave men contaminated by him!
遵命 长官 - 继续努力 中士
Yes, sir. - Carry on, Sergeant.
你是对的 长官 如果没有查出来 这种情绪会传染的
You were right, sir. This sort of thing can spread if it isn't checked.
将军 我相信你的巡视
You know, General, I'm convinced that these tours of yours...
能极大提升这些士兵的士气
have an incalculable effect upon the morale of these men.
我想701团的战斗精神正是来源于此
In fact, I think the fighting spirit of the 701 st derives from it.
不 少校 那来源于他们自己
No, no, Major. That spirit was just born in them.
将军来了 长官
The general is coming, sir.
见到你我总是很高兴 上校 - 荣幸之至 将军
Always a pleasure to see you, Colonel. - I'm honored, General.
这完全是我们的荣幸
It's our privilege entirely.
嗯 你这儿真是小而整洁
Well, quite a neat little spot you have here. - Colonel.
整洁谈不上 长官 不过确实够小的
I reserve comment on the neatness, sir, but it is little.
不好意思 太寒碜了 请坐吧
Pretty shy on seating accommodations though.
对我来说足够了 我没有坐的习惯
More than enough for me. I never got the habit of sitting.
我喜欢站着 时刻处于机动状态
Like to be on my feet. Keep on the move.
这我可以担保 上校 签署命令的时候
我都没办法让将军在桌子后面多坐一会儿
I can vouch for that, Colonel. I can hardly get the general behind a desk long enough to sign an order.
这就是我的方式 你知道的 Dax
Well, that's the way I am, you know, Dax.
我搞不懂那些坐在扶手椅上 想从桌子后面发动进攻的军官
I can't understand these armchair officers...fellows trying to fight a war from behind a desk
向敌人挥舞着文件
waving papers at the enemy...
担心着会不会有老鼠钻进他们的裤腿
worrying about whether a mouse is going to run up their pants leg.
我不知道 将军 如果能从老鼠和枪子之间选 我每次都会选老鼠
I don't know, General. If I had the choice between mice
and Mausers... I think I'd take the mice every time.
我才不信呢,上校
You'll never make me believe that, Colonel.
认真的说 如果是个傻子
Seriously though, if a man's a ninny...
那就让他穿上礼服 藏在床下吧
let him put on a dress and hide under the bed.
但如果他想成为一名士兵 他就必须做士兵该做的
But if he wants to be a soldier, then, by heavens, he's got to be one.
他必须战斗 而他只有待在战场上才能战斗
He's got to fight, and he can't do that unless he's where the fighting is.
这是我的信条 - 我想我只能赞同你
That's my credo. I think I have to agree with you,
你说的太让人信服了 长官
presenting your case so convincingly, sir.
你从来都不会让我们对你的期待落空 - 我觉得你肯定想看看周围情况 不是吗？
And you've never failed to live up to it, sir. - I imagine you'd like a look around, wouldn't you?
是的 上校
Yes, Colonel.
看看这个 Ant Hill
Well, here's something to see.
这是最佳视角了 除非我们占领那里
The Anthill. About as good a view as you can get without actually being there.
呵呵 指日可待了 不是吗？
Well, that won't be long now, will it?
啊
Ah.
嗯
Ah. Yeah.
嗯 我看到更多难以攻克的目标
Well, I've seen much more formidable objectives.
比之前还要困难许多啊
Much, much worse.
嗯 虽然不是我们唾手可得之物
Well, not something we can grab and run away with...
但肯定是可以被攻破的（“可被攻破的”发音与“怀孕”相似）
but certainly pregnable.
虽然听起来有点怪 不是吗？- 为什么？
Sounds kind of odd, though, doesn't it? - Why?
呵呵 说得跟生孩子一样
Well, like something to do with giving birth.
哦 是的 不错 你今天早晨很机灵啊 上校
Oh, yes. Quite. You're right on your toes this morning, Colonel.
甚至比以往更机敏 但我们绝不会忘记
Even sharper than usual.But we mustn't forget,
上校也许是全法国最好的刑事律师
the colonel was perhaps the foremost criminal lawyer in all France.
当然了 将军 - 先生们 你们太客气了
Of course, General. - Gentlemen, you're both much too kind.
告诉我 上校 你们昨晚换防的情况如何？
Tell me, Colonel, how did your relief come off last night?
我们遭到了一些炮击 29人伤亡 长官
We drew some artillery. Twenty-nine casualties, sir.
是的 我在来的路上注意到了 绝对不可原谅 真蠢
Yes, I noticed it on the road in. Utterly inexcusable. Stupid.
所有人如同一群苍蝇般挤在一起 等着被人拍死
All swarmed together like a bunch of flies, just waiting for someone to swat 'em.
似乎他们从来不吸取教训
Well, they never learn, it seems.
在狭窄的地方 猛烈的炮火之下 每次还都挤在一起
They get in a tight spot under heavy fire, gang up every time.
我想这是畜牲的本能 - 某种低等动物的本能
Herd instinct, I suppose. Kind of a lower-animal sort of thing.
我看是某种人类的本能 你分不清这两者的区别吗 少校？
Kind of a human sort of thing, it seems to me...
or don't you make a distinction between the two, Major?
噢 是的 呃 非常不幸 当然
Oh, yes, uh, very regrettable, of course. Very. Yes, indeed.
非常 是的 非常   少校 你能回避一下吗？
Uh, Major, would you be kind enough to excuse us for a few minutes?
遵命 长官 当然可以
Yes, sir. Of course.
上校
Colonel.
好吧 上校 你认为怎么样？
Well, Colonel, what do you think of it?
我认为什么怎么样 长官？
Ant Hill - What do I think of what, sir? - The Anthill.
上校 你们团明天要攻下Ant Hill
Colonel, your regiment is going to take the Anthill tomorrow.
你知道我们的情况 长官 - 噢 当然 一些士兵将不得不牺牲
You know the condition of my men, sir. Oh, naturally, men are going to have to be killed.
可能会牺牲很多 一些士兵将会吃枪子和弹片……
Possibly a lot of them.They absorb bullets and shrapnel...
所以其他人才有可能突破过去
and by doing so make it possible for others to get through.
有什么支援？ - 什么都没有
What support will we have? - I have none to give you.
你预计伤亡情况将会是什么样的 长官？
What sort of casualties do you anticipate, sir?
这么说吧 5%会死在自己人的火力网下 这比通常能够接受的伤亡数字大很多
Hmm, say, five percent killed by our own barrage. That's a very generous allowance.
10%能突破到无人地带
Ten percent more in getting through no-man's-land...
20%能突破到铁丝网
and 20% more getting through the wire.
还剩下65%的士兵 去完成最艰难的部分
That leaves 65% with the worst part of the job over.
假设25%的士兵实际占领了Ant Hill
Let's say another 25% in actually taking the Anthill.
那也足够守住它了
We're still left with a force more than adequate to hold it.
将军 你是说超过一半的士兵将会战死
General, you're saying that more than half of my men will be killed.
是的 可怕的代价 上校
Yes, it's a terrible price to pay, Colonel...
但是 我们将占领Ant Hill  - 但是我们能吗 长官？
but we will have the Anthill  - But will we, sir?
我全靠你了 上校 整个法国就全靠你了
I'm depending on you, Colonel.All France is depending on you.
你觉得我在开玩笑吗 上校？
Am I amusing you, Colonel?
我不是公牛 将军 我不需要面前挥舞的旗帜来激发我的斗志
I'm not a bull, General. I don't need a flag waved in front of me to get me to charge.
我不喜欢你把法国国旗比作斗牛士的斗篷
I don't think I like your comparison of the flag of France to a bullfighter's cape.
我没有不尊重法国国旗的意思 长官
I meant nothing disrespectful to the flag of France, sir.
爱国主义也许过时了 但爱国者是真诚的
Patriotism may be old-fashioned, but show me a patriot, and I'll show you an honest man.
不是每个人都一直这么想 Samuel Johnson对爱国主义发表过不同看法
Not everyone has always thought so. Samuel Johnson had something else to say about patriotism.
我可以问一下是什么看法吗？
And what was that, may I ask?
其实没什么 - “其实没什么”是什么意思？
Nothing really. - What you do mean, "Nothing really"?
拜托 长官 这并不重要 - 上校 我问你的问题 都是重要的
Come on, sir, nothing really important.- Colonel, when I ask a question, it's always important.
这人叫什么？Samuel Johnson（18世纪英国著名作家 批评家） 长官
Now, who was this man? - Samuel Johnson, sir.
好的 他对爱国主义怎么看？
All right. Now, what did he have to say about patriotism?
他说那是无赖的最后一处庇护所 长官
He said it was the last refuge of a scoundrel, sir.
对不起 我不是针对个人
I'm sorry. I meant nothing personal.
你累了 Dax 你很累了
You're tired, Dax. You're very tired.
是你已经筋疲力尽了 而不是你的士兵 是我的失误
我接二连三地给你艰巨的任务
It's you who are exhausted, not your men.And it's my fault.
I've given you one impossible task after another.
你需要休息 非常需要- 我没有说过要休息 长官
You need rest. You need it badly - I haven't said anything about needing rest, sir.
你也绝不会说出来那么 你将不会谈论任何有关休息的事了 上校
And you never would either. Therefore, you're not going to have any say-so about it, Colonel.
因为从现在开始 我下令给你放个无限期的长假
As from right now, I'm ordering you on indefinite furlough.
将军 你不能把我和我的士兵分开 你不能这样对我 长官！
General, you can't take me away from my men. You can't do that to me, sir.
不是对你 Dax 是为了你 为了你和你的士兵们好
Not to you, Dax. For you. For your good and for the good of your men.
为我的士兵好 长官？
The good of my men, sir?
如果一个指挥官缺乏信心 我们还能指望他的士兵有信心吗？
If a commanding officer lacks confidence, what can we expect of his men?
当然 我不是想撤你的职 但我必须得到你热情的支持
Naturally, I don't want to relieve you, but I must have your enthusiastic support.
我需要你说你们可以拿下Ant Hill
Not once have you said that your men can take the Anthill.
我们会拿下Ant Hill
We'll take the Anthill.
如果世界上有士兵可以拿下……
If any soldiers in the world can take it...
那我们就能拿下Ant Hill
we'll take the Anthill.
成功之后 你的部队将会得到一个长假
And when you do, your men will be relieved and get a long rest.
下士Paris和二等兵Lejeune报告 长官
Corporal Paris and Private Lejeune reporting, sir.
你们还真是磨磨蹭蹭啊
You took your time about it.
我们已经尽快准备了 长官 况且我们还要通知哨兵
We prepared as quick as we could, sir.We had to alert the sentries.
好吧 稍息 这是一次侦察任务
All right. You men, at ease. This is a reconnaissance patrol ...
德军的铁丝网 机枪位置 人数
German wire, machine gun posts... identification of bodies.
只有我们三个人 要尽量避免交火
There will only be the three of us, and we're to avoid a fight if we can.
我们从左边出去 然后从右边的6号据点回来
We go out to the left, and we come back through Post 6 on the right.
6号据点的情况如何？ - 所有哨兵都已通知到位
Is everything all clear at Post 6? - All the sentries have been warned up to here.
从4:00起 6号据点会每隔10分钟发射一次照明弹
Number 6 will send up flares at 10-minute intervals starting at 0400.
我希望是每隔5分钟 - 我告诉过他们了 长官
I wanted them every five minutes. - I told them that, sir.
那个中士说5分钟太频繁了 会招来炮击的
The sergeant says every five minutes is too much. He says it's certain to draw artillery.
这位中士是军事家吗？他叫什么名字？
Quite a strategist, this sergeant. What's his name?
我不知道 长官
I don't know, sir.
好的 你们在外面等着 我一会儿就来
All right. You men wait outside. I'll join you in a minute.
请问可以告诉我们行动密码吗 长官？
Would you mind telling us the password, sir?
Calais （也是法国一个城市的名称） - 是的 长官
Calais. - Yes, sir.
他在给自己壮胆 - 那酒闻起来很香啊
He's fortifying himself  - It smelled like heaven.
一看就知道喝了不少 说话这么刻薄
I can always tell when he's had a few. He gets sarcastic.
嗯 至少可以让兄弟们每人都喝点嘛 这个猪头
Well, at least he could have passed it around, the pig.
嘿 他怎么惹你了？
Hey, what's he got against you anyway?
战争爆发前 我们是同学
We went to school together before the war.
他觉得我不够尊重他 他说对了
He thinks I don't have enough respect for him. He's right.
你们准备好了吗？
If you gentlemen are ready.
上校  - 是的 长官 - 了解你们的任务了吗？
Colonel. - Everything clear and understood? Yes, sir.
通过我们铁丝网的通道就在这前面
The lane through our wire is right out in front here.
机枪都对着通道呢
Machine guns are pointing at the opening.
祝你们好运 - 谢谢 长官
Good luck, men  - Thank you, sir.
好的 我们出发
All right, men. Let's go.
那是什么？ - 我不知道
What's that? - I don't know.
Lejeune 过去看看 我们掩护你
Lejeune, move out and look that over. We'll cover you.
你要我们在夜间巡逻中分散开？
Split up a night patrol?
快去 Lejeune
Move out, Lejeune.
我不喜欢这儿 我们走吧
I don't like this. Let's get out of here.
我们要多等他一些时间
We haven't given him enough time.
我们继续等的话 也会被干掉的 - 我们应该等他
If we wait any longer, they'll get us too - We've got to wait for him.
他肯定死了 他在哪儿？
He must be dead. Where is he?
Roget！
Roget!
哇 - 惊讶吧 中尉？
Well  - Surprised, Lieutenant?
是的 很惊喜 我还以为你被打死了
Yes, I am. Happily surprised. I thought you'd been killed.
你没有等在那里确认一下 对吧 中尉？
You didn't wait around to find out, did you, Lieutenant?
你这么说 是什么意思？
Now, look here. What do you mean?
我是说你杀了Lejeune 然后像个兔子似的溜了
I mean, you ran like a rabbit after you killed Lejeune.
杀了Lejeune？你在说什么？
Killed Lejeune? What are you talking about?
我不喜欢你的语气
I don't think I like your tone.
记住 你正在和一位军官说话
You're speaking to an officer. Remember that.
噢 那肯定是我搞错了 长官
Oh, well, I must be mistaken then, sir.
一个军官不会做出这种事的
An officer wouldn't do that.
一个男人不会做出这种事的
A man wouldn't do it.
只有一种东西会
Only a thing would.
一只鬼鬼祟祟的 醉醺醺的 黄肚皮的老鼠 - 你……
A sneaky, booze-guzzling, yellow-bellied rat ...- Now ...
大脑被酒精麻痹 脊梁骨像唾沫一样……
够了 下士！- 你让自己陷入了麻烦当中 中尉？
with a bottle for a brain and a streak of spit where his spine ought to be.
That's enough, Corporal! - You've got yourself into a mess, Lieutenant.
噢 是吗？那么 你让自己陷入了更大的麻烦中
Oh, I have, have I? Well, you've got yourself in a worse one.
第一 不服从上级 第二 威胁你的上司
First, general insubordination. Second, threatening your superior officer.
第三 拒绝服从命令 并煽动其他人也这样做
Third, refusing to obey an order and inciting others to do the same.
你觉得这些指控写在报告里会怎样？
Now, how do you think those charges are gonna look on paper?
与下面这些相比不值一提
Not half as bad as these.
鲁莽行事让士兵身陷险境
Endangering the lives of your men through recklessness.
上岗时酗酒 蓄意杀死战友
Drunk on duty. Wanton murder of one of your own men
面对敌人时胆小如鼠
and cowardice in the face of the enemy.
Phillip 你想指控一位军官吗？
Philippe, have you ever tried to bring charges against an officer?
你知道 是咱俩对质 你觉得他们会相信谁的话？
It's my word against yours, you know. And whose word do you think they're gonna believe?
或者换个说法
Or l-let me put it another way.
他们会接受谁的说法呢？
Whose word do you think they're going to accept?
现在 我告诉你我会怎么做
Now, I'll tell you what I'm willing to do.
到目前为止 我在报告里写的是
So far, all I have written in this report...
你和Lejeune在侦察时牺牲了
is that you and Lejeune were killed while out on patrol.
我会改成 我们在交火中分散之后
I'll fix this to read that you made your way back...
你活着回来了
after becoming separated during the skirmish.
这样就一劳永逸地把事情解决了 - 你杀了Lejeune 你知道的 不是吗？
That'll end the matter once and for all - You killed Lejeune. You know that, don't you?
我很抱歉 那是一个意外 - 你投了手榴弹并且杀了他
I'm sorry. It was an accident - You threw that grenade and killed him.
事实上 如果这件事没有发生 我愿献出一切
I'd give anything in the world if it hadn't have happened, and that's the truth.
老实说 我知道你不喜欢我 但是你以为我是哪种人？
Honestly, I know you don't like me, but what kind of a man do you think I am?
噢 早上好 上校 - 稍息
Oh, good morning, Colonel.- At ease, men.
我一直在等你的报告 - 好的 我们有所发现
I've been waiting foryour report, Lieutenant  - Well, I think we found out a thing or two.
一切顺利吗？ - 不 长官 二等兵Lejeune牺牲了
Everything go well? - No, sir. Private Lejeune was killed.
怎么牺牲的？- 都写在这份报告里了 长官
How'd it happen? - It's all right here in the report, sir.
好的 给我吧 - 还没有写完 长官
Well, let's have it  - Oh, it isn't quite finished yet, sir.
就这样吧 下士 你干的不错
That's all, Corporal. You did a good night's work.
你应该感到自豪 去睡会儿吧
Should feel very proud of yourself. Go get some sleep.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
怎么折了Lejeune的？- 机枪打死的 长官
How'd you lose Lejeune? - Machine gun fire, sir.
他咳嗽了 差点把我们也害死
He coughed. Almost got us all killed.
写完报告立刻交给我
Finish that report and get it to my dugout immediately.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
炮击从5:15开始
The artillery starts at 0515.
一营5:30出发
First Battalion will move out at 0530.
当先头部队清除德军的铁丝网后…
When the leading elements have cleared the German wires...
二营和三营组成的第二梯队
the second wave, consisting of the Second and Third Battalions ...
除去留下2个连作后备 全都出发
minus two companies in reserve ... will move out...
不能迟于5:40
in no case later than 0540.
就这样 先生们 有什么问题吗？
Well, that's it, gentlemen. Are there any questions?
长官 15分钟炮击是我们仅有的支援吗？
Sir, is 15 minutes of artillery preparation all that we can expect?
是的 感觉他们要组织更多炮击需要花太多时间
The feeling is that any more than that will give them too much time to get organized.
明天天气如何 长官？
What's weather supposed to be like tomorrow, sir?
非常好
Too good.
没有雨或者雾吗？
No chance of rain or fog?
预报说整天都是晴天
The forecast is for sun all day.
“如果”――或者我该说“当”我们拿下Ant Hill
lf, uh ... Perhaps I should say when we take the Anthill...
我们要坚守多久才能得到增援？
how long do we have to hold it before we can expect any support?
对了 顺便说一句 Mireau将军 将亲自监督这次进攻
Well, General Mireau, who, by the way, will be personally observing the attack...
他承诺72团将在明天日落时增援
has promised us support from the 72nd by sundown tomorrow...
意思是 当然 我们要坚守一整天
which means, of course, that we'll have to hold all day.
还有什么问题吗？
Are there any more questions?
好吧 先生们 祝你们好运 我肯定你们会像往常一样胜利的
Well, gentlemen, good luck, and I'm sure you'll come through as you always do.
去睡会吧
Let's get some sleep.
我并不害怕死在明天 我只是害怕被杀
[Man Whispering] I'm not afraid of dying tomorrow, only of getting killed.
听不懂你的话 - 你更能接受那种死法？
That's as clear as mud  - Which would you rather be done in by,
刺刀还是机枪？- 当然是机枪
a bayonet or a machine gun? - Oh, a machine gun, naturally.
当然了 这就是我想说的 它们都是用钢铁扎破你的肚子
Naturally. That's just my point.They're both pieces of steel ripping into your guts.
只不过机枪更快 更干净 痛苦更少 不是吗？
Only the machine gun is quicker, cleaner and less painful, isn't it?
这又说明什么？ - 这说明我们大多数人
What does that prove? - That proves that most of us
怕受伤更甚过于怕死亡
are more afraid of getting hurt than of getting killed.
看看Bernard 他最怕毒气 而我一点也不怕
Look at Bernard. He panics when it comes to gas, but gas doesn't bother me a bit.
他看到过被毒死的照片 而我没有见过
He's seen photos of gas cases. Doesn't mean anything to me.
但是我告诉你 我最怕头上没有钢盔 怕得要死
But I'll tell you something though ... I'd hate like the devil to be without my tin hat.
但另一方面 我屁股上有没有钢盔我无所谓
But on the other hand, I don't mind not having a tin hat for my tail.
为什么？- 你应该这样 头部是大脑所在
- Why's that? - You ought to. That's where your brains are.
因为我知道头上的伤势会比屁股上的严重得多
Because I know a wound to the head will hurt much more than one in the tail.
屁股上就是肉 可头上……头上可全都是骨头
The tail is just meat, but the head ... ah, the head is all bone.
随你怎么说 - 告诉我
Ah, speak for yourself - Tell me this.
除了刺刀 你最害怕什么？
Aside from the bayonet, what are you most afraid of?
烈性炸药 - 没错 和我一样
High explosives  - Exactly! And it's the same with me.
因为……因为我知道那会把你炸成碎片
Because ... Because I know that it can chew you up worse than anything else.
你看 就像我告诉你的 如果你真的害怕死亡
Look, it's just like I'm trying to tell you.If you're really afraid of dying,
你下半辈子将一直活在恐惧中
you'd be living in a funk all the rest of your life...
因为你知道你迟早有一天会死 任何一天都可能
because you know you've got to go someday, any day.
此外 如果死亡是你真正的害怕的东西 那为什么在乎是什么杀了你？
And besides, if it's death that you're really afraid of...
why should you care about what it is that kills you?
啊 你太聪明了 教授 我只知道没有人想死
Ah, you're too smart for me, Professor. All I know is nobody wants to die.
师部通讯畅通 长官 直通Polygon
Through to Division, sir. Through to Polygon.
一切平静 各单位都报告准备好了
Everything quiet. All units report themselves ready.
倒计时2分钟
Zero-minus two.
先生们 来点科尼亚克白兰地？
May I offer you gentlemen some cognac?
谢谢 将军 - 谢谢 长官
Thank you, General  - Thank you, sir.
你先 长官
Afteryou, sir.
为法国干杯
To France.
倒计时15 14 13
Minus 15, 14... 13, 12...
10 9 8
11, 10... nine, eight, seven...
7 6 5 4
six, five, four...
3 2 1 0
three, two, one... - zero!
中士 B连在哪？
Sergeant, where's "B" Company?
我不知道 长官
I don't know, sir.
看在上帝的份上 他们在哪？- 在左翼 长官
Where in heaven's name are they? - On the left, sir.
其余的在哪？已经1分钟了 而他们还在战壕里
Where are the rest? Zero-plus one, and they're still in the trenches. They're not advancing.
他们没有前进 可怜的胆小鬼！他们没有前进！
Yes, sir - Miserable cowards. They're not advancing!
炮击点已经离他们很远了！可他们还在战壕里！
The barrage is getting away from them! They're still in the trenches!
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
Nichols上尉
Captain Nichols.
是的 长官？
Yes, sir?
命令75团准备炮击我们自己的阵地
Order the 75s to commence firing on our own positions.
上尉 你听不懂我的命令吗？
Captain, do you fail to comprehend the meaning of my order?
不 长官 但是我请您……
No, sir, but I respectfully ask to ...
上尉 你听不懂我的命令吗？
Captain, do you fail to comprehend the meaning of my order?
不 长官
No, sir.
那就发命令吧 上尉  - 遵命 长官
Then carry it out, Captain  - Yes, sir.
你好 Polygon 这里是师部
Hello, Polygon. This is Division.
炮兵1营和2营准备攻击
Batteries 1 and 2 commence firing...
坐标 32-58-78
on coordinates 32-58-78.
炮兵1营和2营准备攻击
Batteries 1 and 2 to commence firing...
坐标 32-58-78 完毕
on coordinates 32-58-78. Over.
将军 炮兵指挥官报告说 那是自己的阵地
General, the battery commander reports those are our own positions.
他说一定是搞错了
He says it must be a mistake.
确认命令 上尉  - 遵命 长官 没有错误 确认命令
Confirm the order, Captain  - Yes, sir. There is no mistake. The order is confirmed.
炮兵指挥官报告说他不能执行这样的命令
Battery commander respectfully reports he cannot execute such an order...
除非是手写的并且有将军的签名 完毕
unless it is in writing and signed by the general. Over.
炮兵指挥官报告说他不能执行这样的命令
General, battery commander respectfully reports he cannot execute such an order...
除非是手写的并且有将军的签名
unless it is in writing and signed by the general.
把电话给我 - 遵命 长官
Give me that phone! - Yes, sir.
我是Mireau将军
General Mireau speaking!
我是炮兵指挥官 长官
Battery commander speaking, sir.
该部队反叛 拒绝前进 向他们开炮 直到有新的指示！
The troops are mutinying, refusing to advance. Fire as ordered until further notice!
尊敬的长官 你没有权利命令我向自己人开炮
With all respect, sir, you have no right to order me to shoot down my own men...
除非你愿意独自承担一切责任
unless you are willing to take full and undivided responsibility for it.
Rousseau上尉 你执行命令吗？
Captain Rousseau, are you going to obey my order?
我必须接到手写的命令 长官
I must have a written order before I can execute such a command, sir.
假如你牺牲了呢？那我会怎么样？
Supposing you're killed. Then where will I be?
你会在明天早上被枪毙！
You'll be in front of a firing squad tomorrow morning! That's where you'll be!
交出你的指挥权 向我的总部报告 你已经被逮捕了
Hand over your command and report yourself under arrest to my headquarters!
Roget！
Roget!
Roget中尉 为什么你的人还在这里？ - 不可能了 长官 Vignon少校死了
Lieutenant Roget! Why are your men still in here? - It was impossible, sir. Major Vignon is dead.
让这些人冲出战壕！
Get these men out ofthe trenches! Come on!
来吧！让我们再试一次！让这些人冲出去！
Let's get ready for another try! Get these men out of here!
我试了三次了！伤亡严重啊
I've tried three times. Look at all the casualties.
好吧 让我们再试一次！来吧！再来一次
All right! Let's give it another try! Come on! Let's give it another try!
不可能的 长官 所有的人都在撤退了
It's impossible, sir. All the men are falling back.
长官 我服从上校的命令
Sir, I respectfully submit to the colonel ...
但请原谅 你的命令对我很不公平 长官
Pardon, your remarks to me were very unfair, sir.
就是不可能办到嘛 就是不可能
It's just impossible! It's just impossible.
将军 根据第一批报告 进攻已经全线失败
General, according to first reports, the attack has failed all along the line.
士兵们都在撤回战壕
The men are falling back to our own trenches.
Saint-Auban少校 安排701团立即换防
Major Saint-Auban, arrange for the immediate relief of the 701 st Regiment.
送他们到Aigle城堡 让Dax上校到我的总部报道
Have them sent to the Chateau d'Aigle. Have Colonel Dax report to my headquarters.
遵命 长官 - Gouderc少校 召集一个军事法庭
Yes, sir  - Major Couderc, assemble a general court-martial.
明天下午3:00准备好
Have it ready to meet at 3:00 tomorrow afternoon.
这些娘们儿不愿意吃德国的子弹 就让他们尝尝法国的吧！
If those little sweethearts won't face German bullets, they'll face French ones!
我下令进攻 而你的部队拒绝进攻
I ordered an attack. Your troops refused to attack.
我的部队的确进攻了 长官 但是他们攻不上去
Our troops did attack, sir, but they could make no headway.
那是因为他们没有努力 上校  我亲眼见到的 半数人根本就没离开战壕
Because they didn't try, Colonel. I saw it myself. Half of your men never left the trenches.
三分之一的人都被强火力压制住了
A third of my men were pinned down because the fire was so intense.
不要争论细节了 上校
Don't quibble over fractions, Colonel.
事实是 你的人有相当一部分 根本没有离开自己的战壕
The fact remains that a good part ofyour men never left their own trenches.
Dax上校 我要你们团每个连出10个人
Colonel Dax, I'm going to have 10 men from each company in your regiment...
尝尝因为怯懦而判死刑的滋味
tried under penalty of death for cowardice.
死刑？- 因为怯懦！
Penalty of death? - For cowardice!
他们血管中流淌的不是血液 而是脱脂牛奶
They have skimmed milk in their veins instead of blood.
这恐怕是我见过最红的牛奶了！我的战壕被红色脱脂牛奶浸透了！
Then it's the reddest milk I've ever seen. My trenches are soaked with that red skimmed milk.
够了！- 我要直言不讳的说…
That's just about enough out of you, Colonel! - I'm not gonna mince words and stand on protocol ...
Dax上校 如果你的态度一直如此 我将被迫把你逮捕
Colonel Dax, if you continue in this manner, I shall have to place you under arrest.
我认为 上校有他的道理 尽管他过于直率了
I believe the colonel has a point, even though he makes it rather bluntly.
这不是审判 但从某些方面来看是的
This is not a trial, but it does bear certain aspects of one.
Dax上校是在做辩护
And Colonel Dax, technically, is cast in the role of the defense.
从指控的严肃性这一角度来看 法庭将会给予最大的宽容
In view of the gravity of the charges a court of law would grant
him all possible latitude in presenting his case.
宽容是一回事 不服从命令是另一回事
Latitude is one thing. Insubordination another.
我只是提供一个建议 将军
I am merely offering an opinion, General.
请不要勉强接受
Please do not feel constrained to accept it.
我非常乐意接受 Broulard将军
I am perfectly willing to accept it, General Broulard.
对不起 长官 我绝对没有不服从命令的意思
I'm sorry, sir. I certainly didn't intend to be insubordinate.
我唯一的目的是想提醒你 在过去的每一次战斗中
My only aim is to remind you of the heroism these men have shown...
这些士兵所展现出来的英雄气概
on every occasion in the past.
我们不是在谈论过去 我们是在谈论现在
We're not talking about the past. We're talking about the present.
但是你没看见吗 长官？他们不是胆小鬼
But don't you see, sir? They're not cowards.
如果一些士兵没有离开战壕 这命令一定是不可行的
So if some of them didn't leave the trenches, it must have been because it was impossible.
他们接到命令去进攻 服从命令是他们的天职
They were ordered to attack. It was their duty to obey that order.
还轮不到这些士兵来判断命令是否可行
We can't leave it up to the men to decide when an order is possible or not.
如果命令是不可行的 那唯一的证明就是
If it was impossible, the only proof of that...
他们躺在战壕内的尸体
would be their dead bodies lying at the bottom ofthe trenches.
他们是败类 上校
They're scum, Colonel.
整个烂团就是一群 偷偷摸摸的、哀怨的、拖着尾巴的杂种狗
The whole rotten regiment ... a pack of sneaking, whining, tail-dragging curs.
你真的相信是这样吗 长官？
Do you really believe that, sir?
是的 这正是我相信的
Yes, I do. That's exactly what I believe.
更糟的是 这是一个不争的事实
And what's more, it's an incontestable fact.
那为什么不把全团都毙了 我是认真的
Then why not shoot the entire regiment? I'm perfectly serious.
你完全搞错了 我们并不想屠杀整个法军
Now, Colonel, you're missing the point entirely.
We don't want to slaughter the French army.
我们要的是杀鸡儆猴
All we want to do is to set an example.
噢 如果这是你想要的 那就杀我吧
Oh, well, if it's an example you want, then take me.
你？ - 是的 长官 如果你想要杀鸡儆猴
Take you? - Yes, sir, if it's an example you want...
1个人和100个人是一样的
one man will do as well as a hundred.
从逻辑上说 军官应该为这次进攻负最大的责任
The logical choice is the officer most responsible for the attack.
行了 上校 我看你是过度紧张了
Come now, Colonel. I thinkyou're overwrought.
这不是军官的问题
This is not a question of officers.
Paul 我们不想做得太过分
Paul, we don't want to overdo this thing.
只拿12个人如何
Suppose we just make it a dozen.
我刚才说100个人 你现在一下减到了12个
I was talking of a hundred men, and now we're down to 12.
Paul 我们不要再争这个了
Paul, let's not haggle over this thing anymore!
让我们一劳永逸地把这事定下来吧 这样我们都能在这个阴影中继续生活
Let's get it settled once and for all so that we can all live with it.
好吧 也许我太急于见到罪有应得了
Well, perhaps I was a bit too anxious to see proper justice meted out.
我一生都贡献给了军队
I've spent my entire life in the army.
我一直试图忠于自己的原则
I've always tried to be true to my principles.
这是我唯一可以被指责的错误
That's the only mistake I can ever be accused of.
这样定吧
I'll settle for this ...
先从一营每个连中 由连长选出一个人来
have the company commanders select one man from each company in the first wave...
共3个 - 好 非常合理 Paul
three in all  - Well, that's very reasonable of you, Paul.
军事法庭将于下午3:00在城堡开庭
The court-martial will meet at the chateau at 3:00 this afternoon.
这个时间你方便吗？ - 我不会去的 Paul
Will that be convenient for you, General? - I won't be there, Paul.
你不会去？
You won't be there?
是的 我想最好是你自己来处理这个事情
No, I think it best that you handle this matter on your own.
也许是吧
Probably so.
Mireau将军
General Mireau.
如果可能的话 我愿意做被告的辩护律师
If it's at all possible, I'd like to be appointed counsel for the accused.
我会考虑的
I'll take the matter into consideration.
我想我们可以允许 不是吗 Paul？我们当然可以
I think we can permit that, can't we, Paul?  Of course we can.
就这么定了 上校 - 谢谢你 长官
Consider it settled, Colonel  - Thank you, sir.
中午了 Paul 我希望你能留下吃午饭 上校
Well, noon straight up, Paul. I hope that you can stay for lunch, Colonel.
George 恐怕上校没有空
George, I'm afraid the colonel won't have time.
不要否认 Paul 你一直藏着这个人
Don't deny it, Paul. You've been hiding this man, keeping him for your own.
总是为你所用 太自私啦
I think that was very selfish of you.
谢谢你 将军 但是恐怕很快就要3:00了
Thank you for your courtesy, General, but I'm afraid there isn't much time between now and 3:00.
好吧 上校 我会期待下次再见到你
Of course, Colonel. I shall look forward to the pleasure of seeing you again.
上尉 什么事？ - 你叫我来这儿向你报告 长官
Yes, Captain? What is it? - You ordered me to report to you here, sir.
Rousseau上尉 炮兵指挥官  - 是的 是的 当然
Captain Rousseau, battery commander, sir  - Yes, yes, of course.
我想和你谈谈 关于一些炮弹落点很近的事
I wanted to speak to you about some of your shells falling short.
我现在没有时间 回去向你的上级报告 等待进一步的命令
I haven't time to go into it now. Report back to your command until further orders.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir
差劲的部下 使得士气都低落了 - 非常同意你的看法
Bad stuff. Demoralizes the men  - I quite agree with you.
最好的解决办法是搁置不用 把他调离
And the best solution is to shelve him to another outfit.
军事调查委员会应该先严厉批评他一下
A court of inquiry ought to roast him a bit first.
嗯 像炮弹落点很近这种事 我……我总是避免展开调查
Well, in cases like this ... shells falling short ... I ... I always try to avoid an inquiry.
那会给士兵们留下一个坏印象
It gets around among the men and makes a bad impression.
我看 搁置将会是对他最合适的惩罚
No, shelving will be the best discipline for him, in my opinion.
好吧 也许你说得对  - 哦 失陪一会可以吗？
Well, perhaps you're right  - Oh, uh, would you excuse me for a moment?
团里有件事情我想跟上校谈谈
A regimental matter I want to mention to the colonel.
那就餐厅见  - 好的 马上就来
I'll join you in the dining room  - Splendid. In a moment.
Sancy上尉、Renouart上尉和Roget中尉
That will be Captain Sancy, Captain Renouart and Lieutenant Roget.
遵命 长官  - 让他们一个半小时之内到团部来见我
Yes, sir  - Have them meet me at regimental headquarters in half an hour.
遵命 长官  - Dax上校
Yes, sir  - Colonel Dax.
是的 长官  - 我想跟你谈谈
Yes, sir  - I'd like a word with you.
当然 长官
Certainly, sir.
我们都明智一点吧  - 明智 长官？
Let's be sensible about this  - Sensible, sir?
听我说 Dax 别跟我油腔滑调 明白吗？
Listen to me, Dax. Drop this fancy talk with me, understand?
Broulard将军似乎觉得你很风趣 我不觉得
General Broulard seems to think you're funny. I don't.
我要你别再理会这件事  - 你说什么 长官 这是个命令吗？
Now, I want you to drop this affair  - I beg your pardon, sir. Is that an order?
Dax上校 这件麻烦事结束之后 我会修理你的
Colonel Dax, when this mess is cleaned up, I'll break you.
我会找个借口降你的职
I'll find an excuse and I'll break you to the ranks. I'll ruin you.
我会毁了你 你对你的指挥官不忠心
And it'll be just what you deserve...
这是你应得的
showing such little loyalty to your commanding officer.
就这些 上校
That's all, Colonel.
立――定！
Detail, halt!
Mireau将军认为 昨天早晨对Ant Hill的进攻
General Mireau feels that the attack on the Anthill yesterday morning failed...
由于一营的部分士兵不够努力而失败了
because of an inadequate effort on the part of the First Battalion.
你们每个人从你们连选出一个人来
Each of you is to select one man from your company...
逮捕他们 并且带他们到军事法庭
place him under arrest and have him ready to appear before a general court-martial...
不得迟于今天下午15:00
no later than 1500 hours this afternoon.
指控罪名是 面对敌人时怯懦
The charge is cowardice in the face of the enemy.
这是给你们的命令 先生们 去执行吧
You have your orders, gentlemen. Let's carry them out.
但是Roget中尉侦察时杀了Lejeune
But Lieutenant Roget killed Lejeune on that patrol...
还威胁我对整件事情保密！
and then blackmailed me into keeping quiet about the whole thing!
所以他才会选我！ - 下士 我理解你的感受
That's why he picked me  - Corporal, I understand your feelings.
但这件事与你将面临的指控没有关系
But that story has nothing to do with the charges you're being tried for.
你不相信我吗 长官？- 我相信
Don't you believe me, sir? - Yes, I do,
但是别人会信吗？你又没有证人
but who else will? You've got no witnesses.
况且 这种对军官的指控只会惹怒法庭
Besides, such charges against an officer would only antagonize the court.
这件事完了之后 我会再来调查那次侦察的
When we get clear of this, I'm going into the story of that patrol again.
长官 在我们连 Renouart上尉用抽签的方法来选
Sir, in my case, Captain Renouart had the sergeant draw lots.
我被选中纯属偶然
I was picked purely by chance.
你是幸运的 看着我
You're lucky. Look at me.
我被选中是因为 Sancy上尉说我不受欢迎
I was just picked because Captain Sancy said I was a social undesirable.
我 一个不受欢迎的人 上校
Me, a social undesirable, Colonel.
我表现得一点也不怯懦 被抽签选中！这公平吗？- 我也不怯懦！Vignon少校……
I didn't act like a coward. Picking by lots ... is that fair?- Neither did I! Major Vignon ...
先生们！
Gentlemen!
你们得明白 你们被选中的原因不重要
You've all got to understand that the reason you were picked is immaterial.
无论什么原因 你们将接受生死攸关的审判
Whatever the reason, you're on trial for your lives.
坚持你们刚才的说法 不要被检察官所动摇
Stick to the stories you've told me... and don't let the prosecutor shake you out of them.
记住 你们是士兵 在场的都是上级军官
Now remember, you'll be soldiers in the presence of superior officers.
你们的表现要与你们的身份相符
So act like what you are ...
士兵
soldiers.
勇敢的士兵
And brave ones at that.
我去过那审判厅 午后的阳光会照在你们脸上
Now, I've been in the room you'll be sitting in. The afternoon sun will be in your faces...
所以别一副垂头丧气的样子
so don't let it seem as if you're dropping your eyes in a hangdog manner.
回答问题的时候 直视法官的眼睛
When you answer questions, look the judges in the eye.
不要抱怨、申辩或滔滔不绝 那是我的任务
Don't whine, plead or make speeches. That's my job.
简单的陈述 简短
Simple statements ... short...
但是要让审判厅里的每个人都听到
but make them so they can be heard all over the room.
尽量不要重复说过的话 我会为你们总结的
And try not to repeat yourselves. I'll do that for you when I sum up.
时间不多了 大约还有1小时就开庭了
Now, we haven't much time. The court-martial begins in about an hour, and I've got notes to look at.
我还要看看笔记
祝你们好运
Good luck.
谢谢你 上校
Thank you, sir - Colonel, sir.
向左――转！
On the left, ho!
立――定！
Detail, halt!
向左――转！
On the left, ho!
左转！
Left face!
本军事法庭开庭 被告入座
The court-martial is open. The prisoners may be seated.
这是一个普通军事法庭 所以我们应该免除不必要的环节
This is a general court-martial. We shall therefore dispense with unnecessary formalities.
这些人被控在敌人面前表现怯懦
These men are charged with cowardice in the face of the enemy...
将因此而接受审判
and will be tried for that offense.
检察官先生
Mr. Prosecutor.
传被告 二等兵Ferol
Call the accused ... Private Ferol.
主席先生
Mr. President.
检察官询问当事人时 连起诉书都不读吗？
Will the prosecutor question the witnesses without even reading the indictment?
请不要纠缠这些技术细节 浪费庭审时间
Please don't take up the court's time with technicalities.
起诉书那么长 看它有何用
The indictment is lengthy, and there's no point in reading it.
辩护方有权知道确切的被控罪名…… - 起诉书说的是
The defense has a right to know the exact accusations ...
在进攻Ant Hill的过程中
The indictment is that the accused showed cowardice in the face of the enemy...
被告在敌人面前表现怯懦
during the attack on the Anthill.
继续 检察官先生
Proceed, Mr. Prosecutor.
传被告 二等兵Ferol
Call the accused ... Private Ferol.
二等兵Ferol  - 是的 长官？
Private Ferol  - Yes, sir?
当时你在攻击Ant Hill的第一梯队？
Were you in the first wave during the attack on the Anthill?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
你拒绝前进？  - 没有 长官
Did you refuse to advance?  - No, sir.
那你前进了？  - 是的 长官
Did you advance?  - Yes, sir.
你前进了多远？
How far did you advance?
大概到无人地带中部
To about the middle of no-man's-land, sir.
然后你做了什么？  - 到处都是机枪射出的子弹
Then what did you do? There were machine-gun bullets landing all around.
回答问题 你做了什么？
Answer the question. What did you do?
好吧 我看到了Meyer 他也在那儿……
Well, I saw that me and Meyer, sir ...
我没问你看到什么
I didn't ask you what you saw.
法庭不关心你的……“视觉经历”
The court has no concern with your... visual experiences.
我的什么 长官？  - 回答问题
My what, sir?  - Prisoner will reply to the question.
遵命 长官 问题是什么？
Yes, sir. What question was it?
你前进到了无人地带中部 然后你做了什么？
You advanced to the middle of no-man's-land. What did you do then?
然后 长官？  - 你后退了还是前进了？
Then, sir?  - Did you go back or forward?
后退 长官
I went back, sir.
换句话说 二等兵Ferol 你撤退了
In other words, Private Ferol, you retreated.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我问完了 被告可以回到座位上了
That's all. The accused may return to his seat.
等一等
Just a minute.
主席先生 如果可以 我想问当事人几个问题
Mr. President, I'd like to question the witness if I may.
问吧 上校  - 谢谢
Proceed, Colonel - Thank you.
二等兵Ferol 当你达到无人地带中部
Now, Private Ferol, when you reached the middle of no-man's-land...
就只有你和二等兵Meyer吗？
were you alone with Private Meyer?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
那么 你们连其他人上哪去了？
Well, what happened to the rest of your company?
我不知道 长官 我想也许其他人都阵亡了或受伤了
Well, I don't know, sir. I guess the rest of them had been killed or wounded.
你发现你和二等兵Meyer两人 在无人地带中间 处于孤立无援的状态？
And you found yourself in the middle of no-man's-land alone with Private Meyer.
是的 长官  - 你们为什么不独自进攻？
Yes, sir - Why didn't you attack the Anthill single-handed?
为什么你们不独自强行进攻Ant Hill？
Why didn't you storm the Anthill alone?
就我和Meyer？你开玩笑吧 长官
Just me and Meyer? You're kidding, sir.
是的 我是在开玩笑 二等兵Ferol 谢谢你 我问完了
Yes, I'm kidding, Private Ferol. Thank you. That's all.
我不懂你的问题是何意
I don't see the point of this line of questioning.
我是想指出
Well, I'm attempting to indicate, sir...
检察官的问题完全是荒谬的
the utter absurdity of the line of questioning used by the prosecutor.
检察官先生
Mr. Prosecutor.
那么 二等兵Ferol 你坦率地承认 你撤退了？
So you freely admit, Private Ferol, that you retreated.
是的 长官 我和Meyer两个人
Yes, sir. Me and Meyer both.
我知道我们应该拿下Ant Hill 但是我们撤退了
I knew we should've took Anthill, but we came on back.
没有问题了
[Dax] That's all.
被告人可以回到座位上了
The accused may return to his seat.
二等兵Arnaud 你前进了吗？
Private Arnaud, did you advance?
是的 长官 直到Renouart上尉命令撤回战壕
Yes, sir, until I was ordered back to the trenches by Captain Renouart.
你前进了多远？
How far did you advance?
到铁丝网 长官
Into the wire, sir.
我想 是敌军的铁丝网
The, uh, enemy wire, I suppose.
不 长官 是我军的铁丝网
No, sir. It was our wire.
你的意思是你连我军的铁丝网都没有过？
You mean to tell me that you didn't advance any further than our wire?
没有 长官
No, sir, I didn't.
你说那有多远？有多少米？
How far would you say that was? How many meters?
这个 我已经尽力最远了
Well, I advanced as far as I could.
多少米？
How many meters?
没多少米
Not many.
没多少米？
"Not many."
好吧 二等兵Arnaud
Now, Private Arnaud,
在你接到撤退命令之前
before you were ordered back...
你督促你的战友前进了吗？
did you urge your fellow soldiers forward?
大多数刚跨出战壕就被打死或打伤了
Most of them were dead or wounded before they got three steps beyond the trenches.
回答问题
Reply to the question.
我没有督促他们 没有 长官
I didn't urge them on. No, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
二等兵Arnaud 请稍息
Private Arnaud ... At ease, please.
你除了没能竭力激励战友外
Aside from your sad failure to give throat to spirited battle cries
你的行为 从任何方面来说
was your behavior different in any respect from that
和连里的其他战友有区别吗？
of the other men in your company?
反对 这只是个猜测
Objection. That's a matter of conjecture.
反对有效
Sustained.
你们连有人超过我军的铁丝网吗？
Did any men in your company get beyond our wire?
没有 长官
No, sir.
我听说你被指定为懦夫
Is it true that you've been designated a coward...
仅仅是因为你抽出来一张标有“X”的纸片 是这样吗？
simply and purely because you drew a slip of paper marked "X"?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我不觉得这有什么大不了
I don't see that that's significant.
在法军中这种抽签的方式是可以接受的
It's accepted practice in the French army to pick examples by lot.
既然整个连都只前进了几米
And since this entire company advanced only a few meters...
抽签来选已是相当公平的了
picking by lot was eminently fair in this case.
那么 我想要指出这名士兵
Well, I'd like to point out that this soldier has distinguished himself...
已经在几场最惨烈的战斗中证明了自己的优秀
in some of the bloodiest battles of the war.
如果法庭允许 我读一下
With the court's permission...
他因作战英勇而两次获得的嘉奖令
I'll read citations for bravery that he's already earned on two occasions.
第一次 作战英勇嘉奖令……
First, citations in the Orders in the Army for bravery ...
这无关紧要 被告受审是因为他最近的怯懦
That's immaterial, Colonel. The accused is not being tried for his former bravery...
而不是以前的英勇
but for his recent cowardice.
奖章不能用来辩护
Medals are no defense.
我可以传唤证明他品质的证人吗？
May I call witnesses to his character?
不可以
You may not.
但是你可以传唤证明他到达德军铁丝网的证人
But you may call witnesses to the effect that he reached the German wire.
主席先生 整个团没有一个人
Mr. President, no one in the entire regiment...
达到德军铁丝网附近 包括我自己
got anywhere near the German wire, including myself.
如果你问完了 上校
Call the next accused...
传下一被告吧
if you're through, Colonel.
谢谢
Thank you.
被告可以回到座位上了
Prisoner may return to his seat.
你甚至从来没有离开战壕？
[Prosecutor] So you never even left the trenches.
是的 长官  - 我问完了
No, sir  - That's all.
Paris下士 你为什么不离开战壕？
Corporal Paris, why didn't you leave the trenches?
Vignon少校被击中了 他倒下时砸在我的头上 长官 把我砸晕了
Major Vignon was shot, and he fell back on top of me, sir, and knocked me cold.
你在整个进攻过程中一直是昏迷的？
And were you lying unconscious in the trenches during the entire attack?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我问完了 - 有证人吗？
That's all - Have you any witnesses to that?
没有 所有人都忙成一团 没人注意到我 而且地上有很多尸体
No, sir. I guess everybody was too busy to notice me.
And there were so many others lying dead anyway.
但你没有证人？ - 没有 长官
But you have no witnesses  - No, sir.
我只有头上的一个大伤疤 长官
I only have a rather large cut on my head, sir.
那可能是你后来自己弄的
That could have been self-inflicted later.
谢谢你 你可以回去了
Thank you. You may stand down.
检察官先生 你可以陈词了
Mr. Prosecutor, you can make your plea now.
尊敬的各位法官
Gentlemen of the court...
这案子已无需多说
this case speaks for itself.
所有人都目睹了昨天早晨那次不幸的进攻
All of us witnessed the regrettable attack yesterday morning.
我认为这次进攻
And I submit that that attack...
是法国国旗上的污点
was a stain on the flag of France...
是法国
a blot on the honor...
每个男人、女人和孩子的荣耀上的污点
of every man, woman and child in the French nation.
对我们而言 这次任务是一次
It is to us that the sad, distressing...
令人沮丧、痛心、厌恶的失败 法官们
repellant duty falls, gentlemen.
我请求法庭
I ask this court to
判被告有罪
find the accused guilty...
并且根据军事法处以刑罚
and impose the penalties prescribed by the Code of Military Justice.
谢谢 检察官
Thank you, Mr. Prosecutor.
上校 你想陈词吗？
Colonel, would you like to make your plea?
尊敬的各位法官
Gentlemen of the court, there are times when I'm ashamed...
我有时羞于作为人类的一员 现在这种情形就是如此
to be a member of the human race... and this is one such occasion.
要我为辩护方做总结陈词是不可能的
It's impossible for me to summarize the case for the defense...
因为 法庭根本没有给我一个公平的机会来陈述
since the court never allowed me a reasonable opportunity to present my case.
你在抗议这次庭审的真实、可靠性？
Are you protesting the authenticity of this court?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
我抗议 我被阻止出示
I protest against being prevented from introducing evidence...
我认为对辩方至关重要的证据
that I consider vital to the defense.
控方没有任何证人
The prosecution presented no witnesses.
根本就没有一个书面的起诉书
There has never been a written indictment of charges made against the defendants.
最后 我要抗议
And lastly, I protest against the fact...
这次审判没有速记记录
that no stenographic records of this trial have been kept.
昨天早晨的攻击 不是法国荣耀的污点
The attack yesterday morning was no stain on the honor of France...
当然也不是法国军人的耻辱
and certainly no disgrace to the fighting men of this nation.
但是 这个军事法庭
But this court-martial is
才是国家荣耀的污点和法国军人的耻辱
such a stain and such a disgrace.
对这些人的审判 是对人类正义的嘲弄
The case made against these men is a mockery of all human justice.
各位法官
Gentlemen of the court...
判决这些人有罪 将会成为你们的罪行
to find these men guilty...would be a crime to haunt each of you
会困扰你们终生 至死方休
... till the day you die.
我不敢相信 人类最崇高的情感冲动
I can't believe that the noblest impulse of man ...
即对他人的同情心 在这里竟然荡然无存
his compassion for another... can be completely dead here.
因此 我谦逊地恳求你们
Therefore, I humbly beg you...
宽恕这些人吧
show mercy to these men.
把被告押送回警卫室
The accused will be escorted back to the guardroom.
听证会结束 法庭现在休庭审议
The hearing is closed. The court will now retire to deliberate.
卫兵将会是六个人一组 全副武装
There will be a guard of six men under arms ...
步枪上膛 刺刀就位 两人带一个犯人
rifles loaded, bayonets fixed ... two men to each prisoner.
有任何风吹草动 立即把枪对准罪犯
Any sign of trouble, the prisoners will be instantly covered.
如果混乱没有马上平息 就把犯人就地处死
And if the trouble doesn't subside at once, the prisoner will be shot on the spot.
一切都要顺利且迅速
Everything must go off without a hitch with the least possible delay...
但也不能操之过急 绝对不能四处乱走
but it shouldn't be hurried. There must be no fumbling around.
我是负责人
I've been put in charge and made personally responsible...
我对任何混乱和差错负责
for any lack of order or for any mistakes.
但是如果你们任何人失职的话
But you can take it from me that I shall pass on any blame ... and with interest ...
他将替我承担责任
to any one of you who fails in his duties.
根据军事法庭的裁决
Execution will take place
死刑将会在7:00执行
at 7:00 according to the verdict of the court-martial.
立正！注意！解散！
Detail, attention! Dismissed!
这是Mireau将军所赐
This is compliments of General Mireau.
鸭子！- 替我谢谢他 - 噢 不要怪我 士兵
Duck.  - Well, tell him thanks - Oh, don't blame me, soldier.
嘿 丑人 我们用什么吃？手吗？
Hey, ugly, what are we supposed to eat this with ... our fingers?
卫兵说不能让你们拿刀叉
The guard says you can't have any knives or forks.
这可能是我们最后一餐了吗？
Is this supposed to be our last meal or something?
不是“可能” 这肯定就是我们最后一餐了
It isn't "supposed to be" our last meal. It is our last meal.
这鸭子真好吃
Hey, this duck is terrific.
你觉得他们会在食物里下毒吗？
You suppose they put anything in the food?
先毒死我们 再枪毙我们？
First they poison us, then they shoot us?
我认为他们在里面下了药 - 放了什么？
I think they put something in it. Like what?
比如……比如能让我们昏昏沉沉之类的东西
Like, uh ... Like something or make us groggy or something.
他们如果这么做了 也无可厚非
What would be wrong with that if they did?
也许对你来说无所谓 但是我无论如何要出去
Maybe nothing for you, but I'm gonna get out of this somehow...
我不想被下药  - 你要怎么出去？ 在石墙上啃出一条路吗？
and I don't wanna be drugged,How are you gonna get out ... chew your way through that stone wall?
Arnaud Dax上校 他会帮我们的
Colonel Dax, he'll-he'll ... he'll see us through.
听着 我们得出去 否则几小时之内他们就会杀了我们
Listen, we gotta get out of here. They're gonna kill us in a few hours if we don't.
你有办法吗？- 没有 但肯定有办法的
Have you got an idea?- No, but there's gotta be a way.
你觉得外面有多少人在看守？
How many guards you think they've got out there?
可能会有几个警卫 今天早上听起来是这样的
They may have a couple of squads. That's what it sounded like this morning.
也许他们是我们的朋友  - 那些人是三营的
Maybe they're some of our friends  - That's the Third Battalion.
不管怎样 现在我们已经没有朋友了
Anyway, right now, we have no friends.
为什么要欺骗自己？我们出不去的
Why kid yourself? We're not gonna get out of this.
也许你出不去 但是我能出去 我向你保证
Maybe you're not, but I am. I'll guarantee you of that.
看到那只蟑螂了吗？
You see that cockroach?
明天早上 我们会死掉 而它会活着
Tomorrow morning, we'll be dead and it'll be alive.
比起我 它跟我妻子和孩子的联系更紧密
It'll have more contact with my wife and child than I will.
我什么都不是了 而它会活着
I'll be nothing, and it'll be alive
现在你比它强啦
Now you got the edge on 'im.
晚上好 我的孩子们 我是Dupree神父
Good evening, my sons. I'm Father Dupree.
有什么消息吗？ - 恐怕我带来的是很坏的消息
Is there any news? - Yes. I'm afraid I bring you very bad news.
Dax上校要我告诉你们 要做好最坏的打算
You must prepare yourselves for the worst. Colonel Dax asked me to tell you so.
噢 仁慈的上帝 不！- 他已经跟总部通过电话
Oh, mercy! No! - He's been in telephone contact with army headquarters...
但无法找到Broulard将军 或其他有权利过问这件事的人
but unable to speak to General Broulard or, for that matter, to anyone in authority.
师部也是一样 都躲着不接电话
Same way at Division. No one wants to be found.
我们还有多少时间？ - 还有很多时间
How much time do we have? - You have plenty of time yet.
足够你们做好准备
Certainly more than enough to prepare yourselves.
以圣父圣子
In nomine Patris... In the name of the Father ...
圣灵之名
et Filii, et Spiritus Sancti.
阿门
Amen.
神父 可以帮我寄这封信吗？
Father, will you take this letter for me, please?
当然 我的孩子  - 是写给我妻子的
Of course, my son  - It's to my wife.
她不会明白的 我已经尽力解释了
She won't understand this, and I tried to explain it to her.
我保证她会明白的
I'll see that she gets it.
你需要我倾听你的忏悔吗？
Do you want me to hear your confession?
神父 事实上 我不是很信教
Well, Father, to tell you the truth, I'm not very religious.
我知道你想帮我 我很感激
I know you're trying to help, and I appreciate it...
但是如果我现在祷告 我会觉得自己很虚伪
but if I started praying now, I'd feel like a hypocrite.
噢 你错了 孩子
Oh, that's an error, my son.
上帝随时都愿意听你的祷告
God is always ready to listen to your prayers.
好吧 神父 你现在愿意听我忏悔吗？- 是的
All right, Father. Will you please hear my confession now? - Yes.
信仰上帝吧 孩子 我们每个人都会面临死亡
Have faith in your Creator, my son. Death comes to us all.
以圣父、圣子以及圣灵之名
In the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Ghost.
这的确很深刻 “我们每个人都会面临死亡”
That's really deep. "Death comes to us all."
这的确是很深刻
That really is deep.
Ferol 怎么了 担心你的运气无法让你坚持下去？
Say, Ferol, what's the matter... afraid your luck isn't going to hold out?
好吧 瞧！这是……这是……我的信仰
Well, look. This is ... This is my religion.
噢 伟大的酒瓶 原谅我的罪孽 现在我要躺下长眠了
O Great Bottle, forgive me my sins, for now I lay me down to sleep, Bo peep.
我可以先喝一点你吗？谢谢 阿门
May I drink of you first? Thank you. Amen.
我理解你处于极度痛苦中 我的孩子 但你不能任由它使你变得铁石心肠
I understand your anguish, my son... but you must not let it harden your heart.
我能告诉你一些事吗 神父？
May I tell you something, Father?
在我的家乡 有一座小咖啡馆
Back in my hometown, there was a certain little cafe...
吧台上有一条有趣的标语
with an amusing sign over the bar.
是这样写的, “别害怕赊账
It read, "Do not be afraid to ask for credit...
因为我们拒绝的方式是非常礼貌的”
for our way of refusing is very polite."
来吧 Arnaud 坐下 你喝醉了   - 坐下 - 噢 Paris 别管我
Come on, Arnaud,sit down.You're drunk - Come on. sit down -Oh, Paris, leave me alone.
而你 带着你假装虔诚的、油腔滑调的说辞滚出去
And you, get out of here with your sanctimonious pat answers.
你在这里做什么？为了折磨我们？ - 不 为了尽我全部的力量来帮助你们
What are you hanging around for ... to torture us? - No. To help you with all my power.
你的力量？你没有任何力量！- 不 但上帝有力量
Your power? You have no power! - No, but God has power.
他有吗？真好笑 - 你会被拯救的
Does he? What a laugh! - You can be saved.
拯救？我会被拯救！
Saved? I'll be saved!
够了 Arnaud！
Cut it out, Arnaud!
Arnaud！
Arnaud!
Arnaud
Arnaud.
神父 去找医生来 快
Father, get a doctor. Quick.
这会让他保持很长时间的平静 他的颅骨严重骨折
That should keep him quiet long enough.
That's a nasty skull fracture though.
他可能撑不过今晚 - 我们能帮他做什么？
He may not live out the night. What are we supposed to do with him?
我建议把他绑在担架上 这样竖起担架的时候 他就不会滑下来
My advice is to tie him to a stretcher so that he won't slip when you tilt it vertically.
他们不会对伤成这样的人行刑的
Surely they won't execute a man in that condition.
很遗憾 神父 处决依然会执行 我已经和将军确认过了
I'm sorry, Father. The sentence will be carried out. I've already checked with the general on it.
如果他早上还活着 把他抬出去之前捏几下他的脸
If he's still alive in the morning... pinch his cheeks a couple
of times before you take him out on the field.
这会让他睁开眼睛 将军希望他是清醒的
It may make him open his eyes. The general wants him to be conscious.
谁啊？
Yes?
Roget中尉报告 长官- 进来 进来
Lieutenant Roget reporting, sir. - Come in, come in.
Boulanger中士说你要见我 长官
Sergeant Boulanger said that you wanted to see me, sir.
是的 中尉 几个小时后将有一件不愉快的事情要我们处理
Yes, Lieutenant. Looks as if we have a pretty unpleasant thing on our hands in a few hours, doesn't it?
你是指行刑 长官？ - 是的
You mean the execution, sir  - Yes, I mean the execution.
是的 长官 这是一件非常不幸的事
Yes, sir. It's very unfortunate.
哦 非常不幸 我正是这种感觉
Oh, very unfortunate. That's just how I feel about it.
我们都很难过 长官
None of us are happy about it, sir.
你是怎么选出Paris下士的？
How'd you happen to pick Corporal Paris?
我……我必须得选出个人来 长官 是啊 你必须
Well, I ... I had to pick somebody, sir - That's right. You did.
当然 你选出Paris的时候 不是由于个人恩怨 对吗？
Of course, you had no personal motive in picking Paris, did you?
噢 不是 长官
Oh, no, sir.
你选他 是因为他是懦夫 不是吗？
You picked him because he was a coward, didn't you?
是还是不是？
Well, did you or didn't you?
噢 是的 长官 是这个原因
Oh, yes, sir, I did.
诚然 正如你所说 不得不选个人出来
Well ... Like you say, somebody had to be picked.
这是个困难的抉择 长官  - 是的 我现在面对同样的难题
Oh, it was quite a problem, sir  - Yes, I have the same kind of problem.
我必须选个人 负责执行明天的行刑
I have to pick someone to be in charge of the firing squad tomorrow.
你对接受这项任务没有任何异议吧？
Do you have any objections to taking the job?
我？长官？ - 是的 你
Me, sir? - Yes, you.
这…… - 怎么了？你觉得这不好？
Well ... - What's the matter? Don't you feel well?
这…… 不…… 我 我没事 长官 我只是……这儿是不是太热了？
Well, no ... Yeah, l-I feel all right, sir. It's just that I ...- Is it too hot in here?
我去打开窗户？不用 长官 不用
Would you like me to open a window? - No, sir. No, sir.
只是……只是我没有负责行刑的经验 长官
Well, it's ... It's just that I've never been in charge of a firing squad before, sir.
噢 这没啥 首先你帮中士把他们绑在柱子上
Oh, there's nothing to it. First, you help the sergeant tie the men to the posts.
当然 然后如果他们需要 你给他们戴上眼罩
Of course, you offer the men blindfolds. And, well, if they want them, you tie them on, see?
然后 你站在行刑队旁边 举起你的剑
Now, you ...you take your position with the firing squad...you raise your sword
“准备 瞄准 射击”
"Ready, aim, fire."
然后 你拔出左轮手枪 走上前
Then you draw your revolver out, you walk forward...
朝每个人的头上开一枪
and put a bullet through each man's head.
长官 我请求不接受这个任务
Sir, I request that I be excused from this duty.
否决
Request denied.
上校 我……- 你要执行这项任务 任务已经都指派给你了
Colonel, I ... - You've got the job.
就这样  - 上校
It's all yours. That's all, Lieutenant.
如果你可以…… 就这样 中尉！
Colonel, if you could just - That's all, Lieutenant!
谁啊？
Yes?
打扰一下 长官 您是Dax上校吗？ 是的
Excuse me, sir. Colonel Dax? - Yes.
我叫Rousseau 长官  - 我是炮兵上尉
My name is Rousseau, sir, Captain of Artillery.
什么事 上尉？
What is it, Captain?
我有些事要告诉你 长官 也许与军事法庭有很大的关系
I have something to tell you, sir, that may have a great bearing on the court-martial.
进来 中尉
Come in, Captain.
上校 晚上好  晚上好 长官
Well, Colonel, good evening - Good evening, sir.
晚上好 进来坐  谢谢你 长官
Good evening. Come and sit down - Thank you, sir. I ...
我很抱歉 这么唐突地闯到你这里来
I am really sorry to intrude on you in this way.
一点也不 见到你 我总是很高兴 Dax上校 来支雪茄吗？
Not at all. Always delighted to see you, Colonel Dax.Will you have a cigar?
不 谢谢你 长官  但我……
No, thank you, sir, but ...
我想你会发现这酒很好喝
Well, I ... -I think you'll find it delicious.
我很抱歉没有邀请你来参加今晚楼下的宴会
I must apologize for not inviting you to join the party downstairs tonight...
但恐怕这只是些盛装打扮之事
but I'm afraid that it's, uh, a dress affair.
谢谢你 长官 但我得承认
Well, thank you, sir, but I must confess that,
我这次来完全不是社交式的拜访
uh, this is not entirely a social visit.
噢 Dax 别再没完没了地提那件事了
Oh, come, Dax, let's not go over all that ground again.
不过 我必须承认 从伤亡上看
Though, uh, I must admit that, judging from the casualties...
你们团作出的努力还是有目共睹的
the efforts of your regiment must have been considerable.
既然你理解这些 怎么还能让这些人明天被枪决？
Now, how can you understand that and allow these men to be shot tomorrow?
上校 你看问题的角度太简单了
Oh, come, Colonel. You're choosing to take a rather simple view of this thing.
这次攻击从一开始就是不可能成功的 将军们肯定都清楚
The attack was impossible from the start. The General Staff must have known that.
Dax上校 我们认为 我们在战争中表现不错
Colonel Dax, we think we're doing a good job running the war.
你应该清楚 将军们受到了来自报纸和政客们的、各种各样的不公平的压力
You must be aware of the fact that the General Staff... is subject
to all kinds of unfair pressures from newspapers and politicians.
也许进攻Ant Hill的行动是不可能成功的
Maybe the attack against the Anthill was impossible.
也许是我们的判断出了问题
Perhaps it was an error of judgment on our part.
但从另一方面说 如果你的士兵更勇敢一些的话 他们也许能够攻下
On the other hand, if your men had been a little more daring, they might have taken it.
谁知道呢？不管怎样
Who knows? In any case...
为什么我们要为失败承担过多的批评呢？
why should we have to bear any more criticism for failure than we have to.
另一个不能回避的事实是 你的士兵有很多根本就没有离开战壕
Aside from the inescapable fact that a good many of your men never left the trenches...
部队的士气的确有问题 别忘记这一点
there's the question of the troops' morale. Don't forget that.
部队的士气？- 是的
The troops' morale? - Certainly.
处死这些人对整个师来说 将是一剂完美的强心剂
These executions will be a perfect tonic for the entire division.
没有什么比目睹别人的死亡
There are few things more fundamentally encouraging and stimulating...
更能深切地鼓励和刺激人的了
than seeing someone else die.
我从未这样想过 长官 - 你看 上校 部队就像孩子
I never thought of that, sir - You see, Colonel, troops are like children.
就像孩子需要父亲的严格 部队也渴望纪律  - 我知道了
Just as a child wants his father to be firm, troops crave discipline - I see.
维持纪律的方法之一 就是时不时毙掉个士兵
And one way to maintain discipline is to shoot a man now and then.
我能否问一下
May I ask...
你真的相信你刚才说的话？
do you sincerely believe all the things you've just said?
很高兴和你讨论这些 上校
It's been a pleasure discussing this with you, Colonel...
但恐怕我最好还是回去陪我的客人
but I'm afraid that I'd better be getting back to my guests.
请原谅 没让你享受到宴会时光
Forgive me for having kept you from your party.
哦 对了 长官 你是否听说了Mireau将军
Oh, by the way, sir, have you heard that General Mireau...
在这次攻击时 命令自己的炮兵指挥官
ordered his own battery commander, Captain Rousseau...
Rousseau上尉 炮击自己阵地的事？
to open fire on his own positions during the attack? ?
当然 在没有书面命令的情况下 上尉拒绝了
Well, of course the captain refused without a written order...
但是Mireau将军命令他 向我们自己的战壕开火
but General Mireau demanded that he commence firing on our own trenches.
出于同样的原因 Rousseau再一次拒绝了
Again Rousseau refused without an order in writing...
但是将军再下命令 再被拒绝
but again he was ordered, and again he refused ...
这些都有证人
all in front of witnesses.
你真的相信这个不切实际的故事？
Do you actually believe this fantastic story?
这里有几份主要证人的宣誓证词
Here are copies of the sworn statements from all the principals involved ...
炮兵指挥官Rousseau 火炮着弹点观察员Nichols上尉
Battery Commander Rousseau, Captain Nichols, the artillery spotter...
电话秘书和我自己的宣誓证词
the telephone clerk and, uh, my own deposition.
这些和那些被判有罪的犯人之间有什么关系？
What has all this got to do with the charge against the condemned prisoners?
一位将军 在一次本来就不可能成功的进攻失败后
A general in a tantrum over the failure of an impossible attack...
气急败坏地命令他的炮兵向自己人开炮
orders his artillery to fire on his own men.
同一名军官在同一天组织了一个军事法庭
Now, this same officer on the same day...
判决他的三名士兵死刑
orders a court-martial in which three of his men are sentenced to be shot.
将军 你的报纸和政客们知道这些会怎么样？
General, what would your, uh, newspapers and your politicians do with that?
Dax上校 您想威胁我吗？
Colonel Dax, are you trying to blackmail me?
长官 这个词可不好听 但是你现在处境很困难
Sir, that's an ugly word, but you are in a difficult position.
发生了太多的事情 总有人要受到伤害 唯一问题是 伤害谁
Too much has happened. Someone's got to be hurt. The only question is who.
Mireau将军进攻Ant Hill的行动失败了
General Mireau's assault on the Anthill failed...
他下令炮击自己部队的命令被拒绝了
and his order to fire on this own troops was refused.
他为了保护他自己的声誉 企图谋杀三个无辜的人
But his attempt to murder three innocent men...
他的企图将会被将军们制止
to protect his own reputation will be prevented by the General Staff.
请原谅 Dax上校 我已经让客人们等太久了
Will you pardon me, Colonel Dax? I've been rude to my guests too long.
立――定！
Detail, halt!
持枪立正！
Order arms!
行动！
Fall out!
勇敢些 我的孩子 最坏的时候已经过去了
Courage, my son. The worst is over.
早上好 Paris
Good morning, Paris.
早上好 中士 今天感觉如何？
Good morning, Sergeant.
还行吧 你呢？
- How are you today? - Not too bad. How are you?
你错过了昨晚这儿的美餐
You missed some good chow in here last night.
都有什么好吃的？
What'd you have?
给我们带酒了吗？
Have you got a drink for us?
痛快喝吧
Take a swig of this.
这件事居然发生在我身上了 真是好笑 我……
It just occurred to me ... A funny thing.
从庭审到现在我连一次性幻想都没出现
I haven't had one sexual thought since the court-martial.
很了不起 不是吗？
It's pretty extraordinary, isn't it?
起来 像个男人点
Pull yourself together. Act like a man.
听着 Paris 你在听吗？- 是的
Listen, Paris. Are you listening to me?
很多高官、记者都在外面
There will be a lot of dignitaries, newspapermen out there.
你有妻子和家庭 你想留给他们怎样的印象？
You've got a wife and family. How do you want to be remembered?
我不想死
I don't wanna die.
我们中的很多人 在战争结束前也会死的
Many of us will be joining you before this war's over.
我不管 我不想死
I don't care. I don't wanna die.
救救我 中士  - 我救不了你 现在谁也救不了你了
Please save me, Sergeant  - I can't save you. No one can now.
这是你生前有机会做的最后一个决定
This is the last decision you'll have a chance to make on earth.
你可以像男子汉一样站直了 否则我们只有把你拖出去
You can pull yourself together, act like a man, or we'll have to drag you out of here.
最终结果都是一样的 这取决于你
In the end, it'll all be the same. It's up to you.
快点吧 你和Ferol 把外衣脱掉 在这儿耽搁没有意义
Well, let's get busy. You and Ferol take your coats off. It's no use hanging around here.
愿全能的主垂怜我们 赦免我的罪
...with the help of thy grace to do penance
使我得到永生
and to amend my life.
Amen.
为什么我必须死？我到底为什么而死？
Why do I have to die? For what?
为什么我必须死？为什么？我什么也没做
Why do I have to die? Why? I didn't do anything.
我们不要怀疑上帝的旨意 我的孩子
We do not question the will of God, my son.
但是我曾战斗 我曾战斗 我曾在战场上战斗
But I fought. I fought. I fought on the battlefield.
他们为什么不死？为什么不让他们去死？
Why don't they die? Why not put them to death?
你在敌人面前展示了你的英勇 我的孩子
You showed courage in the face of the enemy, my son.
现在在自己的部队面前展示吧
Show it now before your own troops.
但是我害怕 我害怕
But I'm scared. I'm scared.
噢 神父 我好害怕 噢 上帝啊
Oh, Father, I'm scared. Oh, my God.
勇敢点 稳住情绪 士兵 稳住情绪
Courage. Brace yourself, man. Brace yourself.
他说：“这一天 你当与我同在天堂”
He said, "This day, thou shalt be with me in paradise."
真的吗 神父？ - 是的
Really, Father? - Yes.
我再也见不到我妻子了 神父
I don't understand why...
我再也见不到任何人了 神父
I'll never see nobody again, Father. Please.
勇敢点 士兵 稳住情绪
Courage, man. Brace yourself.
我做不到 - 稳住情绪
I can't help it  - Brace yourself.
我做不到 神父 噢 - 上帝 全能的上帝……
I can't help it, Father - O God, O Almighty God ...
噢 基督！基督！- 赐给这个人勇气 他即将面临死亡
Oh, Christ! Christ! Grant courage to this man who is about to die.
赐我力量 上帝！请赐我力量！
Strengthen me, God! Please strengthen me!
为什么我必须死呢 神父？
Why do I have to die, Father?
向后――转！
About face!
绑好囚犯！
Secure prisoners!
全队注意！
Detail, attention!
齐步――走！
Forward march!
立……
Detail,
定！
halt!
向左――转！
Left face!
请别 请别选我……
Please don't. Please choose me to ...
以法国人民的名义
"In the name of the French People...
701团 下士Phillip Paris 二等兵Maurice Ferol
"Corporal Philippe Paris... "Private Maurice Ferol...
二等兵Pierre Arnaud
"and Private Pierre Arnaud... "of the 701 st Regiment...
被判有罪 罪名是在敌人面前表现怯懦
"having been found guilty of cowardice in the face of the enemy...
根据军事法庭的裁决
"are to be executed by rifle fire immediately...
立即执行枪决
in accordance with the judgment of the military court-martial."
向右――转!
Right face!
齐步――走!
Forward hut!
要蒙上眼睛吗？
Do you want a blindfold?
是的 中尉 拜托
Yes, Lieutenant. Please.
我不想死 我不想死
I don't wanna die. I don't wanna die.
要……要蒙上眼睛吗？不
Do ... Do you want a blindfold?- No.
对不起
I'm sorry.
噢 神父
Oh,father
准备！
Ready!
瞄准！
Aim!
射击！
Fire!
我非常高兴你能在那儿 George
I'm awfully glad you could be there, George.
这种事情总是很残酷的
This sort of thing is always rather grim.
但这一次却带有几分辉煌 你不觉得吗？
But this one had a kind of splendor to it, don't you think?
我没见过处理得这么完美的
I have never seen an affair of this sort handled any better.
他们死得干脆利落
The men died wonderfully.
往往会有可能 其中某个人会闹出些乱子 让大家都不爽
There's always that chance that one of them will do something
that will leave everyone with a bad taste.
恐怕没有比这一次更完美的了
This time, you couldn't ask for better.
谁啊？
Yes?
是上校吗？ - 你要见我 长官
Yes, Colonel? You wanted to see me, sir.
噢 是的 是的 请进 上校 进来坐
Oh, yes, yes. Come in, Colonel. Come in and sit down.
噢 Dax上校 你的人死得很好
Oh, Colonel Dax, your men died very well.
喝点咖啡吗 上校？- 不 谢谢你 长官
Would you like some coffee, Colonel? - No, thank you, sir.
噢 对了 Paul 我听说攻打Ant Hill的过程中
Oh, by the way, Paul, it's been brought to my attention...
你命令炮兵向自己人炮击
that you ordered your artillery to fire on your own men during the attack on the Anthill.
我下了什么命令？
I did what?
谁告诉你的？ - Dax上校昨晚来对我说的
Who told you that? - Colonel Dax came to me last night with the story.
Dax上校 我一直很清楚 你不是个忠心耿耿的军官
Colonel Dax, I've always known that you were a disloyal officer...
但是我没想到你会使如此低劣的手段
but I never dreamed that you would stoop to anything so low as this.
将军 我有一些宣誓证词 你的火炮着弹点观察员Nichols上尉的
General, I have sworn statements from Captain Nichols, your artillery spotter...
拒绝执行命令的炮兵指挥官Rousseau上尉的
Captain Rousseau, the battery commander who refused your order.
这太无耻了 极其无耻
I think it's infamous, absolutely infamous.
那Dax上校的指控都不是事实？
Then there's no truth at all to the charge made by Colonel Dax?
难道这还用问吗？
I don't see how you could even ask me that.
你想不到我听你这么说会有多高兴 Paul
You cannot imagine how glad I am to hear that, Paul.
我确信你将顺利度过这一关
I'm certain that you'll come through it all right.
我度过什么？- 不得不展开一次调查
I'll come through what? - There will have to be an inquiry.
调查？- 但不会太多的 这种事情从不会太多 公众很健忘的
An inquiry? - But it won't amount to much. Those things never do. The public forgets.
公众？- 你应该有权澄清自己的名誉
"Public"? - You've got to have the right to clear your name.
你不能允许这些影响你形象的恶劣言辞恣意横流
You cannot allow such vile insinuations against your character to go undenied.
好吧 到此为止吧
So that's it.
你把我当山羊吗
You're making me the goat ...
我才是整个事件中唯一无辜的人
the only completely innocent man in this whole affair.
我只有最后一件事要告诉你 George
I have only one last thing to say to you, George.
被你在背后捅刀子的 是个军人
The man you stabbed in the back is a soldier.
嗯
Well...
不得不这么做
had to be done.
法国不能让傻瓜来决定军队的命运
France cannot afford to have fools guiding her military destiny.
谢谢你 Dax 让我注意到这件事
I'm grateful to you, Dax, for having brought this matter to my attention.
Dax上校 你对Mireau将军的工作怎么看？
Colonel Dax, how would you like General Mireau's job?
他的什么？ - 他的工作
His what, sir? - His job.
我还是开门见山的说吧 长官
Let me get this straight, sir.
你是让我接替Mireau将军的统帅职位？
You're offering me General Mireau's command?
Dax上校 不用过于表现你的惊讶吧
Come, come, Colonel Dax. Don't overdo the surprise.
你从一开始就想要这份工作了 我们都知道的 我的孩子
You've been after the job from the start. We all know that, my boy.
我可能是很多东西 长官 但是我不是你的孩子
I may be many things, sir, but I'm not your boy.
好吧 我当然不是指任何血缘上的关系
Well, I certainly didn't mean to imply any biological relationship.
从任何意义上说我都不是你的孩子 - 你是在激怒我吗 上校？
I'm not your boy in any sense  - You trying to provoke me, Colonel?
我为什么要激怒你？- 没错 如果在晋升之前
Why should I want to do that, sir? - Exactly.
就失去你精心策划而得到的晋升机会
It would be a pity to lose your promotion before you get it...
那将会很可惜
a promotion you have so very carefully planned for.
长官 你想要我来暗示 你有权决定这次职务任免？
Sir, would you like me to suggest what you can do with that promotion?
Dax上校 立刻向我道歉 否则你将会被逮捕
Colonel Dax! You will apologize at once, or I shall have you placed under arrest!
我为对你不够诚实而道歉
I apologize for not being entirely honest with you.
我为隐藏我的真实情感而道歉
I apologize for not revealing my true feelings.
我道歉 长官 因为我没有早点告诉你
I apologize, sir, for not telling you sooner...
你是个堕落的、以他人痛苦为乐的老头子
that you're a degenerate, sadistic old man...
在我向你道歉之前 你可以下地狱了！
and you can go to hell before I apologize to you now or ever again!
Dax上校 你让我很失望
Colonel Dax, you're a disappointment to me.
任凭自己感情用事 令你的头脑不再灵敏
You've spoiled the keenness of your mind by wallowing in sentimentality.
你确实很想救那些人
You really did want to save those men...
你也不觊觎Mireau将军的统帅职位
and you were not angling for Mireau's command.
你是一个理想主义者 我同情你就好像同情一个乡下白痴
You're an idealist, and I pity you as I would the village idiot.
我们在打一场战争 Dax 我们要赢得胜利
We're fighting a war, Dax, a war that we've got to win.
那些人没有战斗 所以他们被枪决
Those men didn't fight, so they were shot.
你控告Mireau将军 所以我坚持让他应诉
You bring charges against General Mireau, so I insist that he answer them.
我哪里做错了呢？
Wherein have I done wrong?
因为你不知道那个问题的答案
Because you don't know the answer to that question...
我可怜你
I pity you.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thank you, thank you.
先生们 我们为你们准备了一点特别的娱乐节目
Now, gentlemen, we have a little special entertainment for you.
就像以前那样 来点儿消遣
Sort of a ... sort of a little diversion as it were.
如同我妻子经常说的 “要是没有点儿消遣 生活还算是什么？”
And as my wife always says, "What is life without a little diversion?"
现在 先生们 我为你们献上 我们最新从敌人手上获得的战利品
Now, gentlemen, I give you our latest acquisition from the enemy.
从德国来的！
- From Germany  - The land of the Hun.
先生们 随着战争的潮汐
Gentlemen, a little pearl washed ashore
冲上岸的一颗小珍珠
by the tide of war.
嘿 讲一种文明人的语言吧
Hey! Talk in a civilized language.
的确 这位年轻的女士有她自身的不足
It's true the little lady has her limitations.
事实上 她绝对没有任何才能
As a matter of fact, she has absolutely no talent at all ...
此外 好吧 也许有一点点天赋
except, that is, well, maybe a little natural talent?
这位年轻的小姐不会跳舞 不会讲笑话
The little lady can't dance, she can't tell any jokes...
也不会用她的小鼻子顶橡皮球
and she can't balance rubber balls on her little nose.
啊 但她的歌声像鸟儿一样 她有一副金嗓子
Ah, but she can sing like a bird. She has a throat of gold.
来吧 宝贝！- 来吧 亲爱的！给我们唱支歌！
- Come on, baby! - Come on, honey! Sing us a song! - Come on, honey! How about a song?
- 来吧 亲爱的！唱支歌！
Come on, baby! Sing us a song!
大点声！大声点！
Louder! Louder!
长官 - 什么事 中士？
Sir - Yes, Sergeant?
我们奉命立刻返回前线
We have orders to move back to the front immediately.
再多给他们几分钟吧  - 遵命 长官
Give the men a few minutes more, Sergeant  - Yes, sir.